George Horace Gallup Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
George Horace Gallup Papers 1936-1979 (bulk 1960-1979)
MSS21865
Gallup, George Horace, 1901-1984
100 items
8 containers
3.2 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Statistician and author. Drafts and printed copies of Gallup's speeches, drafts of books, and Gallup Poll press releases.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Gallup, George, 1901-1984.
Subjects
Public opinion polls--United States.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.
Places
United States--Foreign relations--20th century.; Vietnam--History--1945-1975.
Occupations
Authors.; Statisticians.
Provenance
The papers of George Horace Gallup, statistician and author, were given to the Library of Congress by Gallup between 1964 and 1980. Additions were given by Rita Sappenfield between 1968 and 1969, and by Susan Thompson in 1979.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of George Horace Gallup are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1901, Nov. 18 Born, Jefferson, Iowa
1928 Ph.D., University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa
1929 1937 Professor of journalism and advertising, Drake University, Des Moines, Iowa, Northwestern University, Evanston, Ill., and Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1932 1947 Director of research, Young & Rubicam Advertising Agency, New York, N.Y.
1935 1984 Founder and director, American Institute of Public Opinion
1964 Wrote The Miracle Ahead. New York: Harper and Row
1984, July 25 Died, Tschingel, Switzerland
Scope and Content Note
The papers of George Horace Gallup (1901-1984) span the years 1936-1979, with the bulk of the material dating from 1960 to 1979. The collection consists of speeches by Gallup, drafts of his books, and Gallup Poll press releases from 1979. Final copies of the speeches are contained in bound volumes accompanied by loose drafts and notes. The book file consists of drafts of three unpublished works, on American foreign policy, the Vietnam War, and public opinion surveys, and one published work.
Arrangement of the Papers
Bound speeches are arranged chronologically and loose drafts alphabetically by title. The book file is arranged alphabetically by title.
Container List
- Speeches (Box 1)
  - Bound (Box 1)
    - 1936-1963, (2 vols.) (Box 1)
    - 1964-1973, (7 vols.) (Box 2)
    - 1974-1979, (6 vols.) (Box 3)
  - Drafts and loose copies, 1961-1979, undated (Box 4)
    - A-M, (25 folders) (Box 4)
    - N-W, (24 folders) (Box 5)
    - Untitled (Box 6)
- Books (Box 6)
  - "The Futility of War as an Instrument of United States Foreign Policy," 1970, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - "How to End United States Participation in the Fighting in Vietnam," 1970, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 6, Box 7)
  - "The Intelligent Interpretation and Use of Public Opinion Surveys," 1966, (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 7, Box 8)
  - The Miracle Ahead, 1964, (2 folders) (Box 8)
- Press releases, 1979 (Box 8)